TAREK H. SELEM

Date of Birth: 05th Dec 1991 Egypt, Cairo

Website: https://tarekselem.github.io Skype: t.hamdy91

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/tarek-selem GitHub: https://github.com/tarekselem

SUMMARY:

I have been working as a Software Engineer. I have a strong overall programming experience building Web-based and large-scale systems using Object Oriented Programming languages with 6+ years of experience of building web applications with .Net Framework, MS Dynamics CRM, SPA architecture, JavaScript frameworks.

I always update my knowledge by studying state-of-the-art development tools, programming techniques, and computing equipment, participating in educational opportunities, and reading professional blogs especially for Scott Hanselman, Jon Skeet and Martin Fowler.

EMPLOYMENT:

Senior Software Engineer ITWORX

May 2017 - Present

- Designing and customizing solutions' implementation for scalable projects based on Microsoft Dynamics CRM using .NET and JavaScript.
- System deployment and support on production.
- Building Web APIs and Web Portals.
- Handling integrations between MS Dynamics CRM and other systems using WCF, web APIs, SSIS and windows services.

Senior Solution Developer Link Development (Egypt and KSA) June 2016 – April 2017

- Designing and customizing solutions' implementation for scalable projects based on Microsoft Dynamics CRM using .NET and JavaScript.
- Member of R&D MS Dynamics CRM team.
- Handling integrations between MS Dynamics CRM and other systems using WCF, web services, SSIS and windows service.

Senior Full Stack Developer TMentors March 2015 – May 2016

- Developing web single page applications, windows services, web APIs, mobile applications and unit tests.
- Developing scalable architecture with single sign-on authentication using active directory.
- Supporting technical clients and business users.

Junior .NET Developer EBTCO Software (Egypt Branch) January 2013 – January 2014

- Moving all systems reports from Dev Express to crystal report to be multilanguage and support right to left direction.
- Building security devices integration API's via .NET Sockets Programming.
- Building Asset Management System web application using ASP.NET WebForms.
- Building Content Management System web (CMS) application using ASP.NET WebForms.
- Designing system reports using SSRS.

VB6 Developer, Intern Simple Touch Software January 2010 – December 2012

- Developing ERP system using VB6 and SQL server databases.
- Designing new system reports using Crystal report.
- Executing test cases.

EDUCATION:

Languages: Arabic (Native), English (Fluent), French (A1), German (A2)

Bachelor's degree At Helwan University, Faculty of Commerce, Department of Business Administration (2010-2013)

Course At Telerik, The portal connector for MS Dynamics CRM

Course At ITIDA (SEECC), Modern Software Design Pattern

Course At ITIDA (SEECC), Refactoring to clean code

Course At ITIDA (SEECC), Introduction to Software Project Management

Course At ITIDA (SEECC), Web Development Using ASP.NET

Course At Kit Education Center, Programming With C# Diploma

TECHNICAL EXPERIANCE:

Projects:

1- Urgent Care Extra (USA)

Medical system manages patients, physicians, front desk, payment posters, payment methods like ECheck and credit card and integrates with U.S. medical Epic services. (SPA Architecture, AngularJS, ASP.NET MVC Web API 2, Entity Framework (Code First – Database migrations), MSSQL Server, U.S. health care Epic services, AUTHORIZE.NET payment provider, U.S.P.S Address Provider, Navicare Insurance provider).

2- Implement MS Dynamics CRM For Reliance Home Comfort (Canada)

- Automate sales cycle process.
- Auto calculate commissions for HCAs, Technicians and Sales managers every pay period.
- Syncing and integrating with the other systems.
- (MS Dynamics CRM, C#, JavaScript Plugins, Custom Steps, SSIS, Windows Services, Web API2.

3- Implement MS Dynamics CRM For Ministry of Labor Citizen Account Program (Saudi Arabia)

- Auto syncing millions of applicants and related data with CRM contacts which targets saudian people.
- Tickets management with integration services.
- Auto assigning records based on agent least loaded and round robin approach.
- Handling system notifications via SMS and email.
- FAQs approval module.
- Appeal requests approval module.
- Document Management module.

(MS Dynamics CRM, Plugins, Custom Steps, Kingsway CRM adapter, C#, JavaScript.)

4- Implement MS Dynamics CRM For Ministry of Transportation and Communications (Qatar)

Handles projects stakeholders' submissions cycle of approval with documents management from CRM side and web portal. (MS Dynamics CRM, Plugins, Custom Steps, Telerik Web Portal connector, C#, JavaScript, Telerik controls.)

5- Auto World middleware system (Saudi Arabia)

- Reporting system (PDF, EXCEL, HTML, CSV).
- Schedule Tasks system.
- Notifications Subsystem (Email, SMS, Push Notify).
- Mobile Application (Cross Platform).

(ASP.NET MVC, WEB API 2, Entity Framework, IText, Microsoft Interop components, Windows Service, Azure Bus Service Notification Hub, Xamarin. Forms and MSSQL Server)

6- Shift Payroll System: (Saudi Arabia)

Time attendance logging, system reports and Monthly calculations

(ASP.NET Web Forms, Dev Express Controls, LINQ, MSSQL Server, Crystal Reports)

7- IPunch: (Saudi Arabia)

- Security devices APIs integration.
- Syncing finger print device data with payroll systems.
- Enrolling users.

(WCF, Sockets Programming, ADO.NET, MSSQL Server)

8- Asset Management System: (Egypt)

- Assign tracking tasks.
- Add assets.
- Depreciation calculation.
- Assets Warranties.
- GL Third party integration.
- Printing asset barcode label and RFID tag.

(ASP.NET Web Forms, ADO.NET, Reporting Service, Code Smith Code Generator and MSSQL Server)

9- Content Management System: (Egypt)

managing multiple websites and creating dynamic pages.

(ASP.NET Web Forms, ADO.NET, Code Smith Code Generator and MSSQL Server)

10- Food and Beverage ERP system: (Egypt)

POS, Call Center, Enterprise Chains management and inventory. (VB6, MSSQL Server and Crystal Reports)

LANGUAGES AND TECHNOLOGIES:

- .NET, C#, C++, VB6, Rails, Xamarin
- Microsoft Dynamics CRM, Portal connector, AdxStudio.
- ASP.NET (Web Forms, MVC, Web API 2, WCF), Ruby On Rails.
- JavaScript, Typescript, Angular (1, 2), HTML, CSS.
- MS SQL, Sqlite3, NOSQL, SSIS, SSRS, Scribe.
- Azure (Virtual Machines, service Bus, Blob Storage, Notification Hub, SQL Database, Active Directory).
- Visual Studio, Web Storm, TFS, GIT
- Integrating with hardware devices (Fingerprint, E-lock, Enrollment device, RFID and Robot Joy Stick).